<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>academic on Andrew Xia</title>
    <link>https://qandrew.github.io/tags/academic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in academic on Andrew Xia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 06:46:36 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://qandrew.github.io/tags/academic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Computer Vision to Evaluate Scooter Parking</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/lime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/lime/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m happy to share some of the work I&#39;ve been doing at Lime recently. Mainly collaborating with Yi Su (and with the help of many other co-workers) we were able to train and deploy a computer vision based model to detect whether a scooter is parked in compliance or not through the photos at the end of a trip or scooter deployment. As proper parking is one of the major factors in winning RFPs and the ability to operate in cities, I&#39;m glad that our model can help nudge users to park better and make support micromobility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cryptography Work</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 20:54:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/crypto/</guid>
      <description>Below is a series of summaries of my research in cryptography while I was a student at MIT.
Implementation of a Practical Leakage-Resilient ID Scheme (2016-2018) For my senior year at MIT, I participated in the MIT SuperUROP program as a MITRE Undergraduate Research and Innovation Scholar. My research topic was Implementing Leakage Resilient, Public Key Authentication Systems for Embedded Devices, working with Utsav Banerjee, Chiraag Juvekar and Prof. Anantha Chandrakasan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.875 Cryptography &amp; Cryptanalysis Lecture Videos</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.875/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.875/</guid>
      <description>During the Spring 2018 Semester, I took Vinod Vaikuntanathan and Shafi Goldwasser&#39;s Cryptography &amp;amp; Cryptanalysis (6.875) class. I filmed all but one lecture (oops I lost the video on MPC somwhere in the middle of class), providing a resource for current and future students to access the wonderful lectures. You can view the playlist here. The first recorded lecture is embedded below.
   Selected Press The lecture videos were featured on Hacker News.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORGanized Interactions</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.824/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 20:54:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.824/</guid>
      <description>Context For our final project for the Distributed Systems Class at MIT (6.824), we have successfully implemented a command line interface text editor, such that multiple clients can collaborate on a single document and attain eventual consistency in the document through the use of operational transforms.
View our paper on our implementation here.
The link to the github repository with our source code is available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Digits via Audio-Visual Representations</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.867/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.867/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Our goal is to explore models for language learning (in this case learning numerical digits in their spoken and visual representations) in the manner that humans learn languages as children. Namely, children do not have intermediary text transcriptions in corresponding visual and audio inputs from the world around them; rather, they directly make connections between what they see and what they hear. In this paper, we construct models for the direct bi-directional classification of speech and images, inspired by a few research papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Tic Tac Toe AI</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.115/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.115/</guid>
      <description>For my final project, I built a 3D Tic Tac Toe game, complete with an AI for the user to play against. The input of the game used capacitave based sensing chips, and the output of the game was displayed on a VGA screen. I used my 8051 and R31JP to connect with my PSoC to process the user input and game engine.
Video   Github See my code and documentation here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.854 Advanced Algorithms Lecture Videos</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.854/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.854/</guid>
      <description>During the Spring 2016 Semester, I took Ankur Moitra&#39;s Advanced Algorithms (6.854) class. With the help of my friends Sitara Persad and Shraman Ray Chaudhuri, we filmed all but two lectures, providing a resource for current and future students to access Prof. Moitra&#39;s wonderful lectures. You can view the playlist here. The first recorded lecture is embedded below.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>