<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andrew Xia on Andrew Xia</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Andrew Xia on Andrew Xia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Andrew Xia</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Thresholdizing Lattice-Based Encryption Schemes</title>
      <link>/post/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 20:54:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/thesis/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context-abstract&#34;&gt;Context / Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this thesis, we apply secret sharing techniques on lattice based encryption schemes, namely fully homomorphic encryption and predicate encryption. Using secret sharing techniques from [BGG+17], we show how to construct paradigms of threshold multi-key fully homomorphic encryption and predicate encryption. Through multi-key fully homomorphic encryption and threshold fully homomorphic encryption, we can construct a low-round multi party computation (MPC) scheme with guaranteed output delivery, assuming honest majority in the semi-honest and malicious settings. Applying the secret sharing scheme on predicate encryption constructions from LWE, we can obtain a distributed predicate encryption scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thesis is available &lt;a href=&#34;/files/thesis.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to extend special thanks to my advisor Yael Kalai my collaborator Adam Sealfon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below, I&amp;rsquo;d like to give a high level overview of some of the cryptographic concepts. For more technical details, please see my thesis or the links to the courses below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;secret-sharing&#34;&gt;Secret Sharing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secret_sharing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Secret sharing&lt;/a&gt; is a cryptographic protocol that involves sharing a secret among a group of participants (each receiving shares of the secret), such that the secret can only be reconstructed if a sufficient number of parties combine their shares. The motivation of this primitive is from cryptographic key management, in which storing a secret key would be more secure if split among multiple parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More formally, a secret sharing scheme has two algorithms, $Share$ and $Reconstruct$:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$Share(s, \mathbb{A}) \to (s_1, \dots s_N)$: The share algorithm takes in input secret $s$, an access structure $\mathbb{A}$ for $N$ parties, and outputs $N$ shares in which share $s_i$ is sent to party $i$.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$Reconstruct(S) \to s$: The reconstruct algorithm takes in a set of shares $S$ such that if number of shares in $S$ is sufficient relative to the access structure, then the secret $s$ is returned. Otherwise, $\perp$ is returned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The properties that we want out of a secret sharing scheme are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correctness: if a sufficient number of shares are given to the reconstruction algorithm, then the secret will be recovered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security: if an insufficient number of shares are given to the reconstruction algorithm, then the secret should not be recovered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most famous examples of secret sharing is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shamir%27s_Secret_Sharing&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Shamir&amp;rsquo;s Secret Sharing Scheme&lt;/a&gt; which uses the elegant idea of polynomial interpolation to achieve correctness and privacy. A secret $s$ is simply the $y$ intercept of a degree $n-1$ polynomial $f(x)$, and party $i$ is given $f(i)$ as her share. If $n$ parties combine their shares, through polynomial interpolation it is possible to uniquely reconstruct $s$. However, if there are fewer than $n$ shares available, then it is impossible to uniquely reconstruct $f(x)$ and determine the secret!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/shamir.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shamir&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;Left: unable to determine the polynomial with only two points. Right: uniquely determining a degree 2 polynomial with three points. &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://alexandraalbu.github.io/cryptography/2018/09/27/secret-sharing.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; of image.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fully-homomorphic-encryption&#34;&gt;Fully Homomorphic Encryption&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Homomorphic_encryption#Fully_Homomorphic_Encryption&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fully Homomorphic Encryption&lt;/a&gt; is a recently realized construction which I think is really cool! In essence, it allows computation on encrypted data the same way we would compute on plaintext. An encryption scheme is a family algorithms consisting of $KeyGen$ (which generates the public and secret key, $Enc$ (which takes in as input the public key and a plaintext message and outputs a ciphertext) and $Dec$ (which uses the secret key to decrypt a ciphertext and output a message).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In FHE, we allow an additional $Eval$ algorithm. Assume that $ct_1 = Enc(m_1)$ and $ct_2 = Enc(m_2)$. We can generate $ct^+ = Add(ct_1, ct_2)$ such that $Dec(ct^+) = m_1 + m_2$. We can also generate $ct^* = Mul(ct_1, ct_2)$ such that $Dec(ct^+) = m_1 * m_2$. With addition and multiplication, we can simulate any circuit and this any function! In theory, if you gave your  data encrypted to Google, Google could use FHE to run their algorithms on your data, and return to you the queries you desire, without them learning anything about your underlying data!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;predicate-encryption&#34;&gt;Predicate Encryption&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Predicate Encryption is another type of augmentation of classical encryption schemes. A ciphertext $ct$ is now associated with a private set of attributes $x$ such that one holding a secret key $sk_C$ associated with predicate $C$ can only decrypt $ct$ if $C(x) = 1$. Predicate encryption is a generalization of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attribute-based_encryption&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;attribute-based encryption&lt;/a&gt; but is also a special case of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Functional_encryption&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;functional encryption&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Predicate encryption has many interesting applications. For example, one may wish to encrypt the location of a club meeting with the attributes such that only people who can prove their identity may decrypt and discover the location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-thesis-in-summary&#34;&gt;My Thesis, in summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using secret sharing techniques, we can secret share the secret key of predicate encrytion and fully homomorphic encryption schemes to allow for decentralized decryption. This means that, we can have $k$ parties output partial decryptions of a FHE or PE scheme and be able to reconstruct the output using the partial decryptions, while preserving the secrecy of the secret key shares. Applications of these techniques include low round multi-party computation and decentralized predicate encryption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;further-reading&#34;&gt;Further Reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further reading, MIT&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.mit.edu/6.857/www/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;6.857 Computer and Network Security&lt;/a&gt; class is a good resource to get started in cryptography. I took this class when I was an undergraduate at MIT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also filmed the more theoretical cryptography class at MIT, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ocw.mit.edu/courses/electrical-engineering-and-computer-science/6-875-cryptography-and-cryptanalysis-spring-2005/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;6.875 Cryptography and Cryptanalysis&lt;/a&gt;. The video lectures are available &lt;a href=&#34;/post/6.875/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please see my thesis for a more complete bibliography.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transit in Film</title>
      <link>/post/transit_film/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 11:50:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/transit_film/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently flew from Sao Paolo to Santiago on an Emirates 777-200LR and I watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zhihu.com/question/25154004&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;一生一世&lt;/a&gt; on the flight back. It made me think about how transportation is portrayed in movies and culture in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 一生一世 (But Always), set in China and New York City, the Tongjia Hutong bus station holds a lot of symbolic significance, as a place where the two main characters develop their bond as children. Taking the bus &lt;em&gt;together&lt;/em&gt; as children, connecting in the public space, allowed Anran and Yongyuan to form their relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/transit_ch.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;一生一世&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also recently watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mulholland_Drive_(film)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mulholland Drive&lt;/a&gt; also on my flight on a LATAM 787-8 Dreamliner from Los Ageless back to Santiago de Chile. Earlier that week when I was in LA, I also drove a rental Volkswagen Beetle along Mulholland Drive along the ridge, feeling Hollywood history through the twists and turns of sin and greed. Betty&amp;rsquo;s trips around the city of angels relies on the taxi, and does not promote opportunities to interact with other humans along the journey. For me personally, the closest that I have felt to first world hell is being stuck in the middle of the seven-lane 405 in the middle of rush hour, feeling helpless, alone, and stuck among a sea of cars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/transit_mulholland.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mulholland&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unfortunately the main way to get around Los Angeles is via private cars&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the further past, I also want to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Your_Name&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;君の名は&lt;/a&gt; as another example. In transit-oriented Japan, the train is a key part in life, and Taki and Mitsuha&amp;rsquo;s chance encounters are supported by their daily train rides. When Taki wishes to visit Mitsuha&amp;rsquo;s rural town, he takes multiple trains, a reflection of the transit-oriented culture in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/transit_kimi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mulholland&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my thesis: that transit systems inherently shape human interactions, and the loneliness of the American car, while simultaneously suggesting freedom, is not a medium for social interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transportation is something that is both unifying and distinctive among cultures around the world. Though in the 21st century most big cities around the world have similar urban fabric in highways, subways, bike lanes, and pedestrian walkways, the identity of a city and its people is closely shaped by how people get around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings the question: as our urban mobility changes, how will this affect culture? How will culture and the Hollywood machine react and incorporate ridesharing such as Uber and Lyft in it&amp;rsquo;s depiction of modern times?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, with the rise of last-mile urban mobility in electric scooters and dockless bikes, how will this entry the public sentiment and culture?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerro El Plomo</title>
      <link>/post/el_plomo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/el_plomo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did not summit &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cerro_El_Plomo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cerro El Plomo&lt;/a&gt; this past weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Closing the trip on Sunday night, in Rodrigo&amp;rsquo;s car we descended back down to Santiago from our trailhead, the ski resort of Valle Nevado, at 3000m. The drive back down was a spectacular solace &amp;ndash;up in the mountains, over two kilometers above Chile&amp;rsquo;s primary metropolis, you could see glimpses of the sea of lights peeking between mountain canyons, contrasting the clean clear air and the celestial sky in the highlands with urban civilization, cosmopolitanism, and reality down below. I was a kilometer away from being as close to heaven as I possibly could have been &amp;ndash;the summit standing at a proud 5424m &amp;ndash;when during my summit attempt on Sunday morning I couldn&amp;rsquo;t push on anymore and turned back. On the way down I felt sad because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t summit, but I also held no regrets on my decision, as I am hopeful that I&amp;rsquo;ll have future opportunities to summit higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/1903_el_plomo/afar.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Me&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![Me](/img/1903_el_plomo/vn.jpg) --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cerro El Plomo from afar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although growing up, as a family we went on hikes over the years, I only became more serious about outdoors activities after graduating in 2017. That fall, I drove across the country from San Francisco back to Boston. Purchasing a National Parks Pass and visiting Zion, Grand Canyon, and Canyonlands along the way back sparked my initial interest in exploring more of the wild. I have had exposure to the outdoors, having read &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Into_Thin_Air&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Into Thin Air&lt;/a&gt; for my eighth grade English class and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Into_the_Wild_(book)&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Into the Wild&lt;/a&gt; in High School, and having more time after undergrad allowed me to pursue this hobby &lt;a href=&#34;https://qandrew.github.io/post/hiking/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;more seriously&lt;/a&gt;. In 2018, I took a couple of more serious trips and began my financial investment in the hobby, most notably purchasing a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rei.com/product/127753/deuter-aircontact-lite-65-10-pack-mens&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;backpack&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.marmot.com/never-summer-889169869136.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;sleeping bag&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rei.com/product/880481/nemo-kunai-2p-tent&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tent&lt;/a&gt; &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. My ambitions also increased, hoping to attempt higher peaks and more intense treks as I began to learn more about camping, cooking, and gear management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cerro El Plomo had been on my radar in the months preceding this hike. Since last summer, prior to coming to Santiago de Chile, I had spent my evenings reading about the Andes summits in the area. Cerro El Plomo, with its snow-capped peaks, is the highest mountain visible from Santiago, rising over three miles above the city basin. Every day as I walked or biked around the city, I could see the mountain glistening in the distance, teasing me to a summit attempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had an ambitious plan for the summit attempt this weekend. Mathieu Mari, another fellow exchange student in my lab at Universidad de Chile, and I joined a weekend trip, found via a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/608842662559939/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Facebook Group&lt;/a&gt;. The plan was to meet at Valle Nevado (3000m) at 8am on Saturday, and hike to our campsite, Refugio Federacion (4150m) by the afternoon. The next day, we would begin our summit attempt at 4am, hoping to reach the summit (5424m) by 1pm, and then descend to the campsite, pack up our gear, and return to Valle Nevado by sunset. We would then drive back down to Santiago (600m) to begin the next work week as usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this did not go as planned for me, as I succumbed to altitude sickness once again. Having learned from past experience, I hiked very conservatively and slowly on the first day. As one of the slowest members of the group, I actively told my body not to overwork itself. However, I still ended up throwing up at 3600m halfway to the Refugio, and after the others lightened my load the rest of the way to the campsite, I threw up again at the campsite. Food was not going in my body, and I ate a small dinner somewhat expecting that a third vomit would happen overnight, and slept very soon after arriving at the campsite.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;parallax&#34; style=&#34;background-image: url(http://qandrew.github.io/img/1903_el_plomo/DSC01736.jpg)&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sunset at Refugio Federacion, our campsite at 4100m. Marmolejo, the southernmost 6000m mountain in the world, can be seen in the distance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting myself to wake up the next morning for the summit push at 4am, but I woke up around 3am feeling better than expected. Surprisingly I did not vomit overnight, and I had more energy than to sleep in and do nothing, but I also didn&amp;rsquo;t think I had enough energy to make it all the way. Nonetheless, I joined the rest of the group for the summit push, hiking very slowly at the back. I slowly meandered up the mountain for two hours, each step harder than the one before. Going up for the summit attempt I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how hard I should push myself since on one hand having the mental strength will get me to the peak but on the other hand pushing myself over the limit in these situations can be really dangerous. In the end, close to 4500m, I decided to turn back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the campsite at around 730am as the first rays of the next day began climbing over the Andes to the east. I slept for another four hours, and woke up feeling fairly refreshed and more adapted to the altitude. With nothing else to do, I packed the tent and headed back down to Valle Nevado. If this were a three day trip, maybe the following day I would have been able to push for the summit. I really did want to make it to the top, where I could see Aconcagua, Tupungato, and the other dry Andes greats. But that will have to wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;center&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;container&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;col-xs-4&#34;&gt;
            &lt;iframe height=&#39;405&#39; width=&#39;390&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39; allowtransparency=&#39;true&#39; scrolling=&#39;no&#39; src=&#39;https://www.strava.com/activities/2238424688/embed/b17eeb4e5cfd7facf95fc498a801b4c4e4d84d85&#39;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;col-xs-4&#34;&gt;
            &lt;iframe height=&#39;405&#39; width=&#39;390&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39; allowtransparency=&#39;true&#39; scrolling=&#39;no&#39; src=&#39;https://www.strava.com/activities/2238424154/embed/a0c69bdbae241a4c0d5bc57e1e82884f20076659&#39;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt; --&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;iframe height=&#39;405&#39; width=&#39;590&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39; allowtransparency=&#39;true&#39; scrolling=&#39;no&#39; src=&#39;https://www.strava.com/activities/2238424688/embed/b17eeb4e5cfd7facf95fc498a801b4c4e4d84d85&#39;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe height=&#39;405&#39; width=&#39;590&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39; allowtransparency=&#39;true&#39; scrolling=&#39;no&#39; src=&#39;https://www.strava.com/activities/2238424154/embed/a0c69bdbae241a4c0d5bc57e1e82884f20076659&#39;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;iframe height=&#39;405&#39; width=&#39;590&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39; allowtransparency=&#39;true&#39; scrolling=&#39;no&#39; src=&#39;https://www.strava.com/activities/2238424435/embed/da2a2d2e93e68f5b156a0392697bd8ee3d140327&#39;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mathieu made it to the top, for whom I am very happy for. In the end, five of the eight of our group summited. Mathieu later told me that summiting was probably the hardest physical activity he has ever done in his life. And Ignacio told me in the car ride back, while Gabriel was vomiting by the roadside, that he summited &amp;ndash;but at a great physical sacrifice. I spoke to another group at Refugio Federacion, who successfully summited this time, though also after a failed first attempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this hike, I think my body is not as adept at high altitude. Adding to last summer&amp;rsquo;s shortcomings (the Mt. Fuji trip canceled because of a typhoon, and failing to reach Siguniang&amp;rsquo;s 5000m summit after succumbing to altitude sickness at 4400m), I need to rethink my approach and probably take a slower, more conservative plan for the future. I did achieve a new personal altitude record and I was self-supporting the whole trip, an improvement over Signuiang when I was ferried down by a horse the second day. But while my personal altitude record is over 4400m, I struggle to remember what is the highest mountain I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;em&gt;summited&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash;probably Volcan Villarica in January 2019 at 2847m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is hiking success binary? Did I &amp;ldquo;fail&amp;rdquo; because I didn&amp;rsquo;t summit? Am I just bad at this? Or should I have planned better? Should I have slept more on Friday night, or maybe slept at altitude to acclimate? Why do I even enjoy mountaineering, when I feel more suffering than pleasure at altitude, when I risk brain damage and cannot properly socialize during the trip?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why even climb mountains? &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adventure-journal.com/2017/03/what-everest-climber-really-meant-by-because-its-there/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Because they&amp;rsquo;re there&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; as George Mallory famously said. I want to keep coming back. Even as visitors of US National Parks &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/07/12/opinion/sunday/diversify-our-national-parks.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;do not accurately reflect demographics of the United States&lt;/a&gt;, I want to contribute to the diversity. I want to challenge myself, to push myself to new limits. But I also am unsure how I want to balance my mountaineering and outdoor interests with my work, currently my research in Chile, and my other interests. Am I working hard enough on my actual work, making progress in my research, or am I spending too much time pursuing these hobbies? What &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ap2uWsJV25w&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;kind&lt;/a&gt; $\cdot$ &lt;a href=&#34;https://people.csail.mit.edu/madry/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; $\cdot$ &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jimmy_Chin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;person&lt;/a&gt; $\cdot$ &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2018/10/05/how-the-22-year-old-founders-of-brex-built-a-billion-dollar-business-in-less-than-2-years/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;do&lt;/a&gt; I want to become?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/1903_el_plomo/me.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Me&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Por que hacemos montanas, cuando solo nos sentimos sufriendo?&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, Rodrigo dropped us off at Baquedano and I took an Uber back to my house. I quickly unpacked and called it a night, closing one weekend while awaiting for the next to come. 2019 has been a great year in South America so far, and I am definitely enjoying my experiences in the moment. Hopefully with more focus I&amp;rsquo;ll have a better idea of where to head. And everything should work out in the end :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;I plan on writing more about this in a future blog post! Happy to always talk about gear for hiking.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 2019 Articles</title>
      <link>/post/2019_01_links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 11:50:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019_01_links/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hi all! I thought I&amp;rsquo;d update y&amp;rsquo;all with some of my recent readings/watchings on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;business-articles&#34;&gt;Business Articles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2019/02/micromobility-conference-electric-scooters-bike-share/581791/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Behind the Big Promises of the Micromobility Industry | CityLab&lt;/a&gt; What is the future of transportation? While there is industry hype on self-driving cars, I personally believe that micromobility (dockless bikes and scooters) are the nearer term solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.netflix.com/cl-en/title/81035279&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fyre: The Greatest Party that Never Happened | Netflix&lt;/a&gt; This Netflix documentary, along with Hulu&amp;rsquo;s take on the Fyre festival, is an introspective take on a failed music festival in 2017 and the lead-up to the disaster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bnoUBfLxZz0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Super Fast Logistics of Delivering Blood by Drone | Wendover&lt;/a&gt; Wendover Productions is one of my favorite Youtube channels, and in this video he explains the use of drone to deliver blood in Rwanda, a sub-Saharan African country with universal health care (looking at you, USA).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://levels.fyi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Levels.fyi&lt;/a&gt; This is a nice website to visualize how the career ladder in tech and some similar fields work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kalzumeus.com/2012/01/23/salary-negotiation/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Salary Negotiation tips&lt;/a&gt; Per Eddie Xue, this article touches on points of how to do job negotiations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tech-computer-science&#34;&gt;Tech / Computer Science&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hacker-tools.github.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hacker Tools · hacker tools&lt;/a&gt; a class put together by my friend Anish Athalye and others, I am meaning to go through this to better my engineering skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://timroughgarden.org/f13/f13.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Algorithmic Game Theory | Tim Roughgarden&lt;/a&gt; I am currently going through &lt;em&gt;algorithmic game theory&lt;/em&gt; using Tim Roughgarden&amp;rsquo;s lecture notes (and problem sets and lecture videos) to learn more about the field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ap2uWsJV25w&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ten Years of Being a Software Engineer | Techlead&lt;/a&gt; via Bishesh Khadka, the video below was particularly meaningful and eye-opening to me when I first watched it. Though it pertains much to the perks of the tech industry, it was a very refreshing take on how one&amp;rsquo;s career off the beaten path may lead to unique success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/Ap2uWsJV25w&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;weather-climate&#34;&gt;Weather / Climate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncdc.noaa.gov/temp-and-precip/us-maps/1/201901&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;National Temperature and Precipitation Maps | NOAA&lt;/a&gt; This website provides interesting information on how US weather over the years has deviated from the historical average.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2018/12/24/climate/how-electricity-generation-changed-in-your-state.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How Does Your State Make Electricity? | NYT&lt;/a&gt; Varying by state&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always wondered how much energy the internet uses, and this article provides a rough estimate: &lt;a href=&#34;https://climatecare.org/infographic-the-carbon-footprint-of-the-internet/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Infographic: The Carbon Footprint of the Internet - ClimateCare&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;picture / video: 0.2g CO2 per second&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;email: 4g CO2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;google search: 0.5g CO2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/graphics/2018-us-land-use/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How America Uses Its Land&lt;/a&gt; Bloomberg has a great visualization of land usage in the US: most of our land is dedicated to cattle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/02/02/opinion/sunday/winter-snow-ski-climate.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why Can&amp;rsquo;t Rich People Save Winter? | NYT&lt;/a&gt; This article asks what the ski industry is doing with climate change as an existential crisis for the industry &amp;ndash;and the answer is mostly nothing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;china&#34;&gt;China&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://zarazhang.com/2019/02/06/what-is-it-like-to-work-in-china/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;What is it like to work in China | Zara Zhang&lt;/a&gt; This article by Zara is a more inside take into working in China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=q1QBjpUuflY&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Where Beijing&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;bottom of society&amp;rsquo; live | SCMP&lt;/a&gt; South China Morning Post, based in Hong Kong, provides a more neutral perspective on the Beijing&amp;rsquo;s lower class, and views of the city that tourists otherwise wouldn&amp;rsquo;t see.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;books&#34;&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest, in 2018 I did not read much. I am reading / have finished the following books in January:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_House_of_the_Spirits&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The House of the Spirits&lt;/a&gt; by Isabel Allende.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_to_Win_Friends_and_Influence_People&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to Win Friends and Influence People&lt;/a&gt; by Dale Carnegie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/On_the_Road&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;On the Road&lt;/a&gt; by Jack Kerouac&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope these are interesting for you to read too! If you have any thoughts on these topics, I&amp;rsquo;d love to discuss too!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking in 2018</title>
      <link>/post/hiking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hiking/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I should probably be writing my thesis for my MEng, but I&amp;rsquo;ll start off kindling the writing part of my mind by procrastinating for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past year after I completed my undergraduate degree, I&amp;rsquo;ve been slowing spending more time finding more about who I am. During the MIT undergraduate semesters, which was one of the best times of my life, I had a lot on my plate, from rushing problem set deadline to photography event to party &amp;ndash;it was the work-hard, play-hard lifestyle. But I also was a MIT student, one who tried to take advantage of the school&amp;rsquo;s offering as much as I could &amp;ndash;and in the past fifteen months, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot more time discovering my interests and what are my passions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of those aspects has been hiking, and exploring the outdoors. I drove back from San Francisco to Boston in November / December 2017, and my love for nature began as we bought a national parks pass as we meandered through Utah, Arizona, and Colorado. Since then, I haven&amp;rsquo;t turned back, and this blog post documents some of my adventures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- I&#39;ve also gotten a lot more into cycling after June 2017, specifically spending time in the bay area in Fall 2017 where I really enjoyed the south bay climb. This past fall, I started running more as Kai Xiao, Mike Sun, and I decided to train for a half marathon, and running has been a great re-addition to my life.  --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my workouts and outdoorsy adventures are logged on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/athletes/9473624&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Strava&lt;/a&gt; (where you should follow me!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/d/u/0/embed?mid=1fZz-hmAPbFlJGQVYw3Vrg25bPhzdvlo-&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;480&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;january-the-jay-peak-backcountry-skiing-trip&#34;&gt;January: The Jay Peak Backcountry Skiing Trip&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In January 2018, I went with MITOC Winter school and completed my first backcountry skiing trip. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1359331709&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Strava Activity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/1812_hiking/bigjay.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jay Peak&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Setting up camp that evening, sleeping in -10F was quite an experience; Jan, 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;march-grand-canyon-utah&#34;&gt;March: Grand Canyon &amp;amp; Utah&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over spring break, Saarik Kalia, Sam Judd and I took a week to go hiking in the American Southwest before spending a degenerate weekend in Vegas. We went to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1472260497&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Observation Point&lt;/a&gt; in Zion,
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1473906037&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Navajo Trail&lt;/a&gt; at Bryce Canyon, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1474819093&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Upper Calf Creek Falls&lt;/a&gt; by Rt 12, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1475711502&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Golden Cathedral&lt;/a&gt; in Grand Staircase, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1477122541&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Buckskin Gulch&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1479028348&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Grand Kaibab Trail&lt;/a&gt; in Grand Canyon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;/img/1812_hiking/gc.jpg&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; alt=&#34;GC&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;column&#34;&gt; test &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/1812_hiking/gc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Saarik, Sam, and I&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;On our way to a fifteen mile hike, to the Colorado river and back; Apr, 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/1812_hiking/gcs.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;GCS&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Strava record of the hike&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;april-the-freezing-franconia-ridge-loop&#34;&gt;April: The Freezing Franconia Ridge Loop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April, Jason Liang visited and we decided to go on a winter hike. We chose the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1509013150&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Franconia Ridge Loop&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash;little did we know how &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nationalgeographic.com/adventure/lists/hiking-backpacking/worlds-best-hikes-dream-trails/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;highly ranked&lt;/a&gt; this hike is. Though it was mid-April and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t snow in Boston anymore, we highly underestimated the weather conditions in the whites. Underdressed, by the time we hiked above the treeline it started blizzarding. Both of us ended up with mild frostbite and lessons learned. The epitome of type II fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/1812_hiking/jason.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ominous Clouds&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ominous Clouds as we approach Lafayette; Apr 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;may-acadia&#34;&gt;May: Acadia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May, I went with MITOC on an Acadia trip. David Yang, Linh Nguyen, and I climbed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1597981634&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cadillac mountain&lt;/a&gt; while we were there. I personally found Acadia a bit underwhelming as a national park, especially compared to the sheer magnitude of Grand Canyon, but the views of the ocean from the mountain are quite unique in itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/1812_hiking/acadia.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Acadia&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Views from Acadia, May 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;june-the-presidential-traverse&#34;&gt;June: The Presidential Traverse&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The longest hike I&amp;rsquo;ve ever completed, the Presidential Traverse was an epic sixteen-hour, nineteen-mile adventure. I went with Anish &amp;amp; Ashay Athalye, David Lazar &amp;amp; Joanna, and Max Kessler. I ate four bagels, drank over 5L of water, and had a blast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/1812_hiking/eis.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Eisenhower&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;On top of Mt. Eisenhower with Washington in the background; June 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;august-mt-siguniang-in-china&#34;&gt;August: Mt Siguniang in China&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a trip to Asia this summer, visiting Japan and China. Originally some friends and I wanted to hike Mt. Fuji, but unfortunately there was a typhoon when we visited. In China, I went with my sister and Liang Zhou to Sichuan, where we hiked &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1757762367&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Siguniang Mountain&lt;/a&gt; (四姑娘山). The logistics for getting there was quite an adventure, as hiking in China was not very well documented. I found a driver to drive us from Chengdu to Rilong town via WeChat, and we did not find a guide for hiking the mountain until arriving there. I found Eylene Pirez&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eylenepirez.com/blog/2018/1/17/mount-siguniang-and-all-the-yak-tea-in-china&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; rather helpful for logistics. The mountain consists of four peaks, in which we were attempting the &amp;ldquo;elder sister peak&amp;rdquo; at an elevation of 5025m / 16486ft. I succumbed to altitude sickness at 14,400ft, though my sister and Liang made it to the peak! This was a great cultural experience, and also one where I learned a lot more about the effects of altitude sickness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/1812_hiking/sgn-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Signuiang&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inside our tent at 14.500ft; Aug 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/1812_hiking/sgn-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Signuiang&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- 

&lt;div class=&#34;parallax&#34; style=&#34;background-image: url(/img/1812_hiking/sgn-2.jpg)&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;At the summit of the eldest sister, with the highest peak, the glaciated youngest sister in the distance; Aug 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;september-white-mountain-trips&#34;&gt;September: White Mountain Trips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early fall, I made two trips up to the white mountains again. The first was with MITOC through the August circus, and I spent a day hiking the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1799935480&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kinsmans&lt;/a&gt; and a day hiking Mt. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1799935380&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Moosilauke&lt;/a&gt; via Beaver Brook trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In late September, I went with the MIT Theory group and we hiked &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1859153452&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mt. Liberty&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/1812_hiking/liberty.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Liberty&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;On top of Mt Liberty; Sept 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;november-snoqualmie-mountain-with-sam-judd&#34;&gt;November: Snoqualmie Mountain with Sam Judd&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In November, I took a trip to Seattle for job interviews. I stayed the long weekend in Seattle to see friends, and I also knew that I &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to get a Pacific Northwest hike in. I had heard so many good things about the hiking in Seattle, and, considering it as a city I may move to, I wanted to see how I would enjoy the outdoors. Sam Judd and I went urban exploring and visited &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1959902784&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Vance Creek Bridge&lt;/a&gt;, and we hiked &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.strava.com/activities/1961369704&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Snoqualmie Mountain&lt;/a&gt; the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snoqualmie Mountain was truly a unique hike. Though the length was only 1.5 miles from trailhead to summit, the vertical elevation gain was over 3000ft, resulting in a average gradient of 37%. We transitioned from a early-winter condition with light snow at the trailhead, to a full-on wintry hike with two feet of snow at the top. I was also underdressed for this hike, wearing my running shoes, and only able to glissade down the mountain, but the view on top, with Rainier rising above all so majestically, was unparalleled on such a beautiful day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/1812_hiking/rainier.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rainier&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rainier rising above the rest; Nov 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;november-adams-winter-hike&#34;&gt;November: Adams Winter Hike&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My final hike this year (or maybe this post will be updated over winter break!) was over thanksgiving, when I went with Luke Schaeffer, Anish &amp;amp; Ashay Athalye, my sister and her labmate Matt, and Frederik Mallman. With no wind on the whites, we hiked up Mt. Adams on a clear day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/1812_hiking/adams.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Adams&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Looking higher, with Mt Madison in the background; Nov 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-future&#34;&gt;The future&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be in Chile for eight months next year so hopefully I will get some pretty hikes in and who knows where life will take me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These past few months, I&amp;rsquo;ve also began investing more into hiking equipment. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll make a blog post sometime writing about my gear, and what I find helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August 2018 Articles</title>
      <link>/post/2018_08_links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 11:50:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018_08_links/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I keep a journal entry to write down my thoughts and also my day to day life (who I hang out with, where I eat etc), though recently I decided to also start keeping track of my digital history, a series of links of articles / websites that I&amp;rsquo;ve found interesting. Here are some that I&amp;rsquo;d like to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;transit-articles&#34;&gt;Transit Articles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2018/08/how-america-killed-transit/568825/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why Is American Mass Transit So Bad? It&amp;rsquo;s a Long Story | CityLab&lt;/a&gt;: this is a good CityLab article about the history of public transit in the US, it&amp;rsquo;s rise in the early 20th century, and its demise as automobiles became more prevalent in this country in the ensuing decades.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vox.com/2018/8/27/17676670/electric-scooter-rental-bird-lime-skip-spin-cities&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Electric scooters: why Bird, Lime, Skip, and Spin are taking over cities | Vox&lt;/a&gt;: Dockless bikes, electric scooters, and even electric mopeds are coming soon to your city! This article is a nice intro/summary about this new transit medium.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yH8tqrnvNQE&amp;amp;t=71s&amp;amp;list=WL&amp;amp;index=29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Predicting Intersection Signal Timing | Youtube&lt;/a&gt;: A Simons Institute Lecture on how traffic signals work and the technical details behind the scene.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;china&#34;&gt;China&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5Bi6hbbzl-E&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Extreme poverty in China: Only 3 kids left in a shrinking Chinese village | Youtube&lt;/a&gt;: here is an interesting video that shows the countryside of China. While when tourists visit China, they may be mesmerized by China&amp;rsquo;s world-class high speed rail, or the tremendous development in cities in the past few decades, it is worth noting that there are still regions in China that struggle with poverty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;athletics&#34;&gt;Athletics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal for this fall is to complete a half marathon, and to have a good cycling routine. Cycling a lot this summer has helped me build my endurance. Here are some relevant articles / videos that may be inspiring:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.buzzfeed.com/michellekhare/i-went-from-hating-running-to-running-a-marathon-in-ten?utm_term=.clWGwBPQb#.aeVKp2j6E&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I Ran A Marathon With Only Ten Weeks Of Training And It Was Intense | Buzzfeed&lt;/a&gt;: here is a BuzzFeed video on training for a half marathon. Though cliche in certain aspects, I did find it inspiring (and how does she claim to be bad at long distance running if she ends up qualifying for the Boston Marathon 🤔)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zenlabsfitness.com/7-different-types-of-running-to-do/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Try These 7 Different Types of Running Workouts! (Beginner to Advanced)&lt;/a&gt;: different types of runs (beyond simply doing long, endurance runs) that might be good for running training. I&amp;rsquo;m a novice runner, so there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to learn for me!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.wahoofitness.com/the-ultimate-guide-for-tracking-your-cycling-heart-rate/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Ultimate Guide for Tracking Your Cycling Heart Rate | Wahoo Fitness&lt;/a&gt;: An article about different heart rate zones that cyclists (and runners) should consider when training.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;other&#34;&gt;Other&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pitchfork.com/best/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Best New Music | Pitchfork&lt;/a&gt;: I recently discovered this website! It does album reviews which has helped me discover more music.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@lenjibin/why-crazy-rich-asians-is-important-to-me-8a59cada7c98&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Why Crazy Rich Asians is Important — to me | Benji Lin&lt;/a&gt;: My friend Benji wrote a summary about watching Crazy Rich Asians.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.realclearpolitics.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;RealClearPolitics - Opinion, News, Analysis, Video and Polls&lt;/a&gt;: Recommended by my friend Hongyi, this is a website that aggregates news about politics, seemingly the equivalent to HackerNews for tech.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope these are interesting for you to read too! If you have any thoughts on these topics, I&amp;rsquo;d love to discuss too! I should cite &lt;a href=&#34;https://lycarter.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Landon Carter&lt;/a&gt; as an inspiration for this blog post format.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Urban Planning and Such</title>
      <link>/post/2018_urban/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 11:50:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018_urban/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hello, and I guess I am back to [attempting to] blogging. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try to consolidate my thoughts and interests on urban planning and related topics in this blog post. Growing up, I&amp;rsquo;ve always had an interest in transportation related topics. Whether it be city planning, trains (mass transit or high-speed rail), airplanes, or cars, my interests have drifted in and out of these areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2017_tube.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tube&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clapham North, one of the two remaining stations in the London Underground with a true deep-tube island platform. July, 2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always found this topic very fascinating, probably due to growing up in big cities like Tokyo. Though I am a computer scientist by training, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that I will find some area in the future where I can apply my computer science skillset in this domain. I find work by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://senseable.mit.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Senseable City Lab&lt;/a&gt; or research by people like &lt;a href=&#34;http://wucathy.com/blog/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cathy Wu&lt;/a&gt; to be very inspiring. Industry options like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sidewalklabs.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sidewalk Labs&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://getcruise.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cruise &lt;/a&gt; are places that I may wish to work at in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, while I am not working on my research, I do spend time reading and thinking about these topics. Below are a series of links that I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed following and reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;blogs&#34;&gt;Blogs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some blogs that I follow (somewhat regularly):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pedestrianobservations.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pedestrian Observations&lt;/a&gt;: This is a blog I found some time ago that provides a lot of detailed analysis on cities and their transit planning options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://citylab.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CityLab&lt;/a&gt;: This is a news site run by the Atlantic which contains a lot of interesting posts about city-related topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/whatwouldjanejacobsdo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;New-Urbanist Memes for Transit Oriented Teens&lt;/a&gt;: This is the classic high-traffic Facebook group consisting of a healthy mix of transit-related memes and fruitful discussion. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Urbanist_Memes_for_Transit-Oriented_Teens&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;). There are derivative groups that focus on bicycles, aircrafts, and other topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://yelling-at-trains.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Yelling at Trains&lt;/a&gt;: This is run by my friend Ian Reynolds, who had his live map of the Boston MBTA featured on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bostonglobe.com/metro/2015/09/25/mit-student-builds-real-time-mbta-map-into-wall-using-led-lights/Jizvo3C8iqs64kcgbJRR5N/story.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the Boston Globe&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;airplane-related-resources&#34;&gt;Airplane Related Resources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d say that I am currently (c.2018) in a lull in terms of my aviation interests. In late 2017 I was paying close attention to United&amp;rsquo;s Boeing 747 retirement event. I was interning in the San Francisco Bay Area, where the last of the Boeing 747s were based, and in my twelve weeks in the bay area I probably visited San Francisco International Airport about ten times. Evan Yao and I were able to attend the &lt;a href=&#34;https://thepointsguy.com/2017/10/united-747-family-day/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;United&amp;rsquo;s 747 Farewell Family Day&lt;/a&gt;, through winning a twitter sweepstakes hosted by ThePointsGuy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2017_747.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tube&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;The last international flight of United&amp;rsquo;s 747 Friend Ship, UA892, landing. October, 2017&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, there are probably a lot more interesting topics about airplanes. &lt;a href=&#34;https://skift.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Skift&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://centreforaviation.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CAPA&lt;/a&gt; provide interesting analysis on the business or product side of the aviation industry. For travel blogs or tips on churning, I defer to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flyertalk.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FlyerTalk&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://onemileatatime.boardingarea.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OneMileAtATime&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://thepointsguy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ThePointsGuy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To follow airplanes in particular, I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://planespotters.net&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Planespotters&lt;/a&gt; to look up airplane inventory. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flightradar24.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FlightRadar24&lt;/a&gt; is my go to for tracking flights or airplanes. Certain airplanes, such as the Lufthansa 747-8I retrojet (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.planespotters.net/airframe/Boeing/747/D-ABYT-Lufthansa/4XRZHqQN&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;D-ABYT&lt;/a&gt;) or the ANA 787-9 Star Wars Jet (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.planespotters.net/airframe/Boeing/787/JA873A-All-Nippon-Airways/AeRQTe1R&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;JA873A&lt;/a&gt;) deserve special attention!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2016_787.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tube&#34; /&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;ANA&amp;rsquo;s Star Wars Jet, a Boeing 787-9 Dreamliner. January, 2016&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;on-the-academic-note&#34;&gt;On the Academic Note&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I am currently a masters student doing graduate research, one thing I&amp;rsquo;ve also been thinking about is what area I could get in to work on these problems. Maybe working on railway scheduling problems or algorithms to design traffic intersections in the advent of self driving cars would be interesting. To this note, I&amp;rsquo;ve also been working in what direction I can head in the future. On the more policy or design-oriented field would be Urban Studies, such as MIT&amp;rsquo;s department of Urban Studies and Planning. There is also work in the Civil and Environmental Engineering Departments, and Operations Research is also an area where research is done in this area. Finally, controls and algorithms will be useful for these problems, to which Computer Science departments may also have work in this area. I came across the Simons Institute Spring 2018 &lt;a href=&#34;https://simons.berkeley.edu/programs/realtime2018&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Real Time Decision Making Program&lt;/a&gt; which may have interesting leads for academic directions one may want to pursue. I also apologize in advance for my lack of understanding in this field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you do happen to stumble across this blog, please get in contact with me as I love talking about these things! If there are any other links / sites that I&amp;rsquo;ve missed, let me know too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.875 Cryptography &amp; Cryptanalysis Lecture Videos</title>
      <link>/post/6.875/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/6.875/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;During the Spring 2018 Semester, I took Vinod Vaikuntanathan and Shafi Goldwasser&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://stellar.mit.edu/S/course/6/sp18/6.875/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cryptography &amp;amp; Cryptanalysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (6.875) class. I filmed all but one lecture (oops I lost the video on MPC somwhere in the middle of class), providing a resource for current and future students to access the wonderful lectures. You can view the playlist &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL6ogFv-ieghe8MOIcpD6UDtdK-UMHG8oH&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The first recorded lecture is embedded below.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/jDsfV2ohFPs&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;selected-press&#34;&gt;Selected Press&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lecture videos were featured on &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=17840024&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips on Basic Financial Management</title>
      <link>/post/moneybasics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 14:19:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/moneybasics/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Continuing from my previous post &lt;a href=&#34;../creditcard&#34;&gt;on credit cards&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll detail some of my money management habits that might be helpful for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about opening bank accounts, maximizing rewards, and some basic investment tips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bank-accounts&#34;&gt;Bank Accounts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open a savings account like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gsbank.com/savings-products/online-savings.html?cmpid=ps-GSB-rGGLgsONLNlsa6354327&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GS Bank&lt;/a&gt; and earn 1.2% interest every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn.thewirecutter.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/cash-back-credit-card-2x1-fullres-2-1024x512.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not have a bank account, I would definitely recommend getting one. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to have money stored in a bank rather than having to carry cash around, make purchases on the internet, and certain banks also offer nice interest rates so your money will grow by just sitting there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two main types of bank accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first, a &lt;strong&gt;checkings account&lt;/strong&gt; is essentially a digital wallet. Your checkings account will usually come with a &lt;strong&gt;debit card&lt;/strong&gt; that you can use to spend from your checkings account. Usually checkings accounts do not offer interests, since there are no restrictions to how many withdrawals you can make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second kind is a &lt;strong&gt;Savings Account&lt;/strong&gt;. With this account type, you might only be able to withdraw 6 times a month, with an upper bound of how much money you can take out. However, as the bank gains some amount of long-term consistency on your money, they will also give you higher interest rates. At a 1% interest rate, leaving $10,000 in your savings account will earn you $100 a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, only money that you need to spend in the short term should be in your checkings account. All of your other financial worth can be in your savings account, or in investments (mentioned below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nerdwallet has a nice page on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nerdwallet.com/banking/best-savings-accounts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;best savings accounts&lt;/a&gt;. I recently opened a GS Bank Online Savings account, which offers a 1.2% annual interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bankofamerica.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bank of America&lt;/a&gt; is good for checkings accounts since they have a lot of ATMs across the country for cash withdrawal, and there is also a BoA office at MIT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;maximizing-reward-programs-discounts&#34;&gt;Maximizing Reward Programs / Discounts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;open all the loyalty programs, and receive extra points in addition to your normal spending habits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nerdwallet has a nice summary of beginner tips for maximizing points and miles &lt;a href=&#34;https://thepointsguy.com/guide/beginners/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll give a quick summary of that page below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/thepointsguy.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Screen-Shot-2016-07-13-at-11.31.45-AM.jpg?fit=2048%2C2048px&amp;amp;ssl=1&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for airline loyalty programs&lt;/strong&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re going to fly Delta anyway, might as well get miles for it (which will eventially translate into free flights)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign up for airline dining programs&lt;/strong&gt;. You can &amp;ldquo;double dip&amp;rdquo; when dining out by earning airline miles in addition to credit card rewards. For example, dosa factory in Boston offers 3 miles/$ in addition to your &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nerdwallet.com/blog/credit-cards/capital-one-premier-dining-rewards-credit-card-review/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;3% cash back&lt;/a&gt; credit card for dining (so that&amp;rsquo;s 6% off).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opentable.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OpenTable&lt;/a&gt; to make dining reservations (you get a $20 gift card after making ~20 reservations) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.restaurant.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Restaurant.com&lt;/a&gt; for discounts at restaurants you want to go to (for example, you can buy a $10 Beantown Taquiera credit for only $4).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make purchases through &lt;strong&gt;online shopping portals&lt;/strong&gt;. Click through one of the online mileage malls and you’ll automatically get points or miles for every dollar you spend. If you buy an iPhone, use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://shopping.mileageplus.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;United&lt;/a&gt; shopping portal to go to Apple&amp;rsquo;s website, and also earn extra 700 miles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blogs-to-follow&#34;&gt;Blogs to follow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some blogs that I recommend following for maximizing rewards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://thepointsguy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Thepointsguy&lt;/a&gt; is a very useful blog that provides useful information on travel perks and maximizing rewards. I essentially followed this &lt;a href=&#34;https://thepointsguy.com/guide/beginners/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;beginner&amp;rsquo;s guide&lt;/a&gt; to create this blog post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nerdwallet.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Nerdwallet&lt;/a&gt; offers good advice on credit cards, bank accounts, and investing brokers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.travelpirates.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Travel Pirates&lt;/a&gt; is a nice blog that has links to cheap travel deals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;investing&#34;&gt;Investing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Please keep in mind that my observations are from an amateur perspective; investing carries its risks and make sure you have done your research before making purchases!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is that, if you have extra money lying around, if you leave it in cash, after a year it will have the same face value. Leaving it in a bank can have it grow by 1% a year. Investing [in stocks] might yield more growth, but also risk losing money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t detail investment strategy in this blog post, but I&amp;rsquo;ll mention some companies through which you can invest your money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To buy stocks, you usually need to go through &lt;strong&gt;Brokers&lt;/strong&gt;. I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;http://share.robinhood.com/andrewx6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Robinhood&lt;/a&gt; since it has no &lt;a data-toggle=&#34;tooltip&#34; title=&#34;Usually, for every transaction, you have to pay ~$7 to the broker&#34;&gt;commission&lt;/a&gt; on trades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may also want to make investments through an &lt;strong&gt;IRA&lt;/strong&gt; (individual retirement account). With tax deductions, you can earn more on your investments. The two main types of IRAs are the Roth and Traditional, as compared below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Roth&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Traditional&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Maximum Annual Salary&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$118k&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;none&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fidelity.com/retirement-ira/contribution-limits-deadlines&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Maximum Annual Contribution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$5,500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;$5,500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rothira.com/traditional-ira-vs-roth-ira&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;taxed before contribution&lt;br&gt;investment earnings aren&amp;rsquo;t taxed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;deductible before contribution&lt;br&gt;investment earnings are taxed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A safe investment option for IRAs is to buy S&amp;amp;P 500 ETFs (for example through &lt;a href=&#34;https://personal.vanguard.com/us/funds/snapshot?FundIntExt=INT&amp;amp;FundId=0968&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Vanguard&lt;/a&gt;, which is essentially taking a neutral stance on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, get a ROTH IRA account while you are still a poor student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, &lt;strong&gt;Cryptocurrencies&lt;/strong&gt; like Bitcoin and Ethereum have been hot investment topics, with Bitcoin fourfolding this calendar year and Ethereum tenfolding. You can use &lt;a href=&#34;https://coinmarketcap.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Coinmarketcap&lt;/a&gt; to follow the cryptocurrencies, and invest through 3rd parties like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coinbase.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Coinbase&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://libertyx.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LibertyX&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ## &lt;span style=&#34;color:#222&#34;&gt;Blogs to follow&lt;/span&gt; --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are some tips that I&amp;rsquo;ve spent time researching, hopefully they are helpful for you too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, feel free to contact me and I love talking about these things!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips on Credit Cards</title>
      <link>/post/creditcard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/creditcard/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hello, this is my first blog post in a while :) I&amp;rsquo;ll keep to a minimalist writing style so reading this blog can be as fast and as helpful as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;credit-cards&#34;&gt;Credit Cards&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nerdwallet.com/blog/nerdscholar/credit-card/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;credit card&lt;/a&gt; is a payment system. When you use a credit card to buy an item, you are effectively borrowing money from the bank, and you can pay the bank back within a subsequent 25-30 day period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A credit card is offered by a bank (Bank of America, Chase). Visa and MasterCard are payment networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-should-i-get-one&#34;&gt;Why should I get one?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build your &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nerdwallet.com/blog/category/finance/credit-score/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;credit score&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fraud protection&lt;/strong&gt;: if you purchased a fradulent item, and you want to cancel the purchase, with a credit card, you can call the bank and get your money back (the bank assumes the risk). However, if you purchase such item with a debit card or cash, your money has been spent and cannot be retrieved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rewards&lt;/strong&gt;: many credit cards may offer 2% cash back, which means you are saving money every time you buy an item.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foreign Transaction Fees&lt;/strong&gt;: if you travel frequently, there are credit cards with no foreign transaction fees, which might be a better exchange rate than going to a counter. (Though, different credit card networks may offer different conversion rates).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-shouldn-t-i-get-one&#34;&gt;Why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t I get one?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tendencies to &lt;strong&gt;overspend&lt;/strong&gt; with credit cards lead to debt accumulation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interest rates&lt;/strong&gt; for paying the debt are very high. If you pay on time, though, there is no debt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;things-to-look-for-when-choosing-a-credit-card&#34;&gt;Things to look for when choosing a credit card&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there an &lt;em&gt;annual fee&lt;/em&gt;? Usually the credit cards with better rewards also have an annual fee ($95/year), so if your spending&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Foreign transaction fees&lt;/em&gt;? When using a credit card abroad, you may be charged up to 3% extra for the purchase. However, this fee is waived for many cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Signup bonus&lt;/em&gt;? Some credit cards may offer 30,000 miles (or cashback) for the first $1000 you spend in the first 3 months of opening a card, which may be a tremendous value!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rewards&lt;/em&gt;? This is the key part of credit cards -taking advantage of the rewards! Whether you prefer cashback, airline miles, AMC movie discounts, etc, you should choose a card that best fits your needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;which-credit-cards-should-i-get&#34;&gt;Which credit cards should I get?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I am a student, the credit cards that I&amp;rsquo;m mentioning are targeted towards my spending category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;general-usage&#34;&gt;General Usage&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These credit cards have rewards that are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.nerdwallet.com/images/4220_729390816ccdb615ef999cd87032af4f_L.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Credit Card&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By far, I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.citi.com/credit-cards/credit-card-details/citi.action?ID=citi-double-cash-credit-card&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Citi Double Cash Card&lt;/a&gt;. You get 2% cash back on every single purchase with no restrictions. No annual fees, but there is a foreign transaction fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(However I think the fineprint states that to get the 2nd percent cash back, you must wait for the transaction to be confirmed before you pay back. Essentially, wait a while before you actually make your credit card payment for this card.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.nerdwallet.com/images/3214_dba0115abf776ec818e0e8c96368e362_L.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Chase&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://creditcards.chase.com/a1/freedom-unlimited?CELL=6B4W&amp;amp;jp_cmp=cc/Freedom%20Unlimited_Brand_Exact_Freedom%20Unlimited_SEM_US_No%20xLOB_Standard_NA_MMTest/sea/NmfddVbu/Chase%20Freedom%20Unlimited&amp;amp;kwdID=NmfddVbu_dc&amp;amp;adgrpID=207361584940&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chase Freedom Unlimited&lt;/a&gt;, which offers 1.5% cash back, and no annual fees. This credit card also offers $175 back for the first $500 you spend in the past 3 months, so it&amp;rsquo;s better than the Citibank card for up to the first $35,000.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://res.cloudinary.com/value-penguin/image/upload/fl_png8,f_auto,q_90/v1438118632/credit_cards/ztwxtj1e26gh6d2y8rqu.png&#34; alt=&#34;BoA&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also have the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.valuepenguin.com/bankamericard-better-balance-rewards-card&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BankAmericard® Better Balance Rewards™ Credit Card&lt;/a&gt;. You essentially get $100 caskback every year as long as you pay in full, so it&amp;rsquo;s a nice credit card to have to get the flat rewards. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it&amp;rsquo;s offered anymore, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;airline-rewards&#34;&gt;Airline Rewards&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the cards that generally I&amp;rsquo;d apply to, and then CANCEL them once I get the initial rewards so you don&amp;rsquo;t get charged the annual fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.nerdwallet.com/images/1010_cc47a1a5ee39357fc30b0956ac636838_L.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Delta&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently have the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.americanexpress.com/us/credit-cards/card/delta-skymiles/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Delta Gold SkyMiles&lt;/a&gt; card. Currently, you earn 30k miles (roughly $400) for the first $1k you spend, which is a 40% discount rate! You also get 1 free check-in baggage when flying Delta, and priority boarding, and no foreign transaction fees. The annual fee of $95 is waived the first year, so be sure to cancel it in the first year :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that the initial miles bonus varies over time (I got 60k miles when I applied), so you may also want to wait for a better miles deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.nerdwallet.com/images/4001_10e0b458979cb0521292536baee76173_L.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AA&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had the &lt;a href=&#34;https://secure.fly.aa.com/citi/direct-plat?anchorLocation=DirectURL&amp;amp;title=citi&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;American Airlines Citibank&lt;/a&gt; credit card. You also earn 30k miles for the first $1k you spend, plus similar perks with the Delta credit card. I got the initial bonus, and cancelled it because of the annual fee. However, holding onto the credit card is still nice because I can show the card to the gate attendants at the airport and occasionally get priority boarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.nerdwallet.com/images/3049_12169088ebdb44fed1214e8549a23e72_L.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;United&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, there&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www2.theexplorercard.com/40kAF?CELL=B4W&amp;amp;jp_cmp=cc/United%20Explorer_Brand_Exact_United%20Explorer_SEM_US_No%20xLOB_Standard_NA_MMTest/sea/18GOqH4i/Chase%20United&amp;amp;kwdID=18GOqH4i_dc&amp;amp;adgrpID=211099896667&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;United Chase&lt;/a&gt; credit card. Currently you get 40k miles for the first $1k you spend, and similar perks and annual fee. I don&amp;rsquo;t have this yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you fly other airlines more frequently, feel free to look up their credit cards and their perks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;general-tips&#34;&gt;General Tips&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup autopay from your bank account, and always pay in full&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a credit card as early as possible to build your credit score&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay to have multiple credit cards open, but make sure you keep track of the finances in such cards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! This is meant to be an introduction to credit cards, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t go into many of the rewards details (technically the Chase credit card reimburses you in Chase UltimateReward points which then you can convert to cash, or miles).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll try to write on Investing (Robinhood, Bitcoin, Vanguard, RothIRA) next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leakage Resilient Public Key Authentication for Embedded Devices</title>
      <link>/post/2017_superurop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 16:09:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017_superurop/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;For my senior year at MIT, I participated in the MIT SuperUROP program as a MITRE Undergraduate Research and Innovation Scholar. My research topic was &lt;em&gt;Implementing Leakage Resilient, Public Key Authentication Systems for Embedded Devices&lt;/em&gt;, working with &lt;a href=&#34;http://chiraag.scripts.mit.edu/wiki/start&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chiraag Juvekar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-mtl.mit.edu/~anantha/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prof. Anantha Chandrakasan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was presented at EECScon. An extension of this work, with my collaborators, is currently in submission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having an effective and convenient authentication system
is necessary for the future development and increased
usage of devices in the Internet of Things. This
paper presents the implementation of a pairings-based,
public key leakage resilient authentication system to
improve upon current authentication schemes. We have
developed a pairings library in C, and we have implemented
software in RISCV assembly that successfully
implements such authentication scheme on a FPGA,
demonstrating the feasibility and efficiency of such primitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My paper can be found &lt;a href=&#34;/files/superUROP.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic Lightning</title>
      <link>/post/6.857/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/6.857/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;For our &lt;a href=&#34;http://courses.csail.mit.edu/6.857/2017/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;6.857 (network security)&lt;/a&gt; final project, in a group project with Jamie Bloxham, Gina Yuan, and Justine Jang, we implemented probabilistic payments on the bitcoin lightning project. The bitcoin lightning is a peer-to-peer system that allows transactions between parties to be conducted off the main blockchain, reducing transaction costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt; With regular Bitcoin transactions, low-value, high-frequency payments are increasingly impractical due to increasingly significant mining fees that must be paid with each transaction. The Bitcoin Lightning Network is an extension to Bitcoin that allows two parties to create a payment channel between themselves, allowing payments to be made without committing many transactions to the blockchain, thus avoiding substantial mining fees. However, these payments still cannot be smaller than a satoshi, the smallest unit of Bitcoin. In this paper, we describe a
scheme for probabilistic payments in the Lightning Network, which can be utilized to effectively make sub-satoshi microtransactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/6857_lit.png&#34; alt=&#34;Lit&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;github&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See my code and documentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jbloxham/lit&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our final writeup can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/9be2/024e080adfaf545c7efae3a5114056e5cef3.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;selected-press&#34;&gt;Selected Press&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our project was featured on &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitcointechweekly.com/briefs/probabilistic-lightning-sub-satoshi-transactions-in-the-lightning-network/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bitcoin Tech Weekly&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/7jwohp/these_kids_from_mit_propose_a_technique_for/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORGanized Interactions</title>
      <link>/post/6.824/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 20:54:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/6.824/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our final project for the Distributed Systems Class at MIT (6.824), we have successfully implemented a command line interface text editor, such that multiple clients can collaborate on a single document and attain eventual consistency in the document through the use of operational transforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View our paper on our implementation &lt;a href=&#34;/files/6.824.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link to the github repository with our source code is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qandrew/6.824-fp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack Punt Tool</title>
      <link>/post/hpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 06:47:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hpt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with MIT Student Cable, I helped film MIT&amp;rsquo;s Musical Theater Guild (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mit.edu/~mtg/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MTG&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&amp;rsquo;s IAP 2017 production of &lt;em&gt;Hack, Punt, Tool&lt;/em&gt;, which is an original musical about a fictional group of MIT students working on building a Hack at MIT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please enjoy the video below!

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/IPpqXyo4jhM&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lenses we used included a Nikon 70-200mm f2.8, Panasonic 7-14mm f4.0.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>/talk/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Academic&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further talk details can easily be added to this page using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
