<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>photovideo on Andrew Xia</title>
    <link>https://qandrew.github.io/tags/photovideo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in photovideo on Andrew Xia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 06:46:36 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://qandrew.github.io/tags/photovideo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>6.875 Cryptography &amp; Cryptanalysis Lecture Videos</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.875/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.875/</guid>
      <description>During the Spring 2018 Semester, I took Vinod Vaikuntanathan and Shafi Goldwasser&#39;s Cryptography &amp;amp; Cryptanalysis (6.875) class. I filmed all but one lecture (oops I lost the video on MPC somwhere in the middle of class), providing a resource for current and future students to access the wonderful lectures. You can view the playlist here. The first recorded lecture is embedded below.
   Selected Press The lecture videos were featured on Hacker News.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack Punt Tool</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/hpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 06:47:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/hpt/</guid>
      <description>Context Along with MIT Student Cable, I helped film MIT&#39;s Musical Theater Guild (MTG)&amp;lsquo;s IAP 2017 production of Hack, Punt, Tool, which is an original musical about a fictional group of MIT students working on building a Hack at MIT.
Please enjoy the video below!   The lenses we used included a Nikon 70-200mm f2.8, Panasonic 7-14mm f4.0.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer 2016 Vlogs</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/2016_videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 06:47:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/2016_videos/</guid>
      <description>Context During the summer of 2016, I made a series of vlogs documenting my travels through Asia. My friend Jingyi Zhao and I took a one week trip to Thailand before heading to Tokyo for a week to participate in the MUSCAT program organized by the university of Tokyo. Here are four videos that I made documenting the trip.
1. Flight to Thailand   2. Bangkok   3. Chiang Mai   4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.854 Advanced Algorithms Lecture Videos</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.854/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.854/</guid>
      <description>During the Spring 2016 Semester, I took Ankur Moitra&#39;s Advanced Algorithms (6.854) class. With the help of my friends Sitara Persad and Shraman Ray Chaudhuri, we filmed all but two lectures, providing a resource for current and future students to access Prof. Moitra&#39;s wonderful lectures. You can view the playlist here. The first recorded lecture is embedded below.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>