<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Andrew Xia</title>
    <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Andrew Xia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://qandrew.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Close to the Fire</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/close_to_the_fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/close_to_the_fire/</guid>
      <description>This year has been an interesting year to say the least. I recently hit my 1 year mark at Lime; by now I&#39;ve almost worked remotely longer than I have worked in the office. My San Francisco roommates Brian, Grace, Jason and I have a good routine at our apartment. We enjoy each others&amp;rsquo; companies as we cook, chat, and play games together. We&#39;ve lost much &amp;ndash;the ability to connect with our friends in person, the ability to mingle with our co-workers at the office, the ability to do so much of what normal life entailed &amp;ndash;but as much as my life has been affected, I would still consider myself very lucky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started With Cycling</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/bike/</guid>
      <description>Recently, due to COVID related lockdowns, a lot of my friends have been getting into cycling! I thought I&#39;d write a series of blog posts on how to get into cycling and what to look for.
Why do I enjoy cycling? For me, I started cycling in Fall 2017, after I had completed my undergraduate, and I was looking to pick up a new hobby. My friend Brian Axelrod introduced me to road biking, which I really enjoyed, especially climbing up the South Bay hills during my internship at Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Computer Vision to Evaluate Scooter Parking</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/lime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/lime/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m happy to share some of the work I&#39;ve been doing at Lime recently. Mainly collaborating with Yi Su (and with the help of many other co-workers) we were able to train and deploy a computer vision based model to detect whether a scooter is parked in compliance or not through the photos at the end of a trip or scooter deployment. As proper parking is one of the major factors in winning RFPs and the ability to operate in cities, I&#39;m glad that our model can help nudge users to park better and make support micromobility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>El Eclipse Solar</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/eclipse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/eclipse/</guid>
      <description>I had been wanting to see a solar eclipse since when I first learned about them in first grade, and I distinctly remember in second grade while I was doing 体操 at 图强二小, I would look up directly at the sun, hoping to see an eclipse, and my mind would play games with me simulating how an eclipse may look. As a relatively rare natural phenomenon, occurring once every 18 months in a very lucky region of the world, it had always been my dream to witness one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to travel the Last Mile: Urban Mobility Options</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/lastmile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/lastmile/</guid>
      <description>Hi! As a passionate transit-oriented teen, I wanted to write this blog post to detail how multi-modal transportation options can be used to best fit one&#39;s transportation needs. For context, I am currently a student based in Santiago de Chile (May 2019).
Here are my realistic transportation options:
 I could either walk or run, as my human-powered mobility options. I could bike (or ride an electric scooter, skateboard etc), if I owned these micromobility options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April 2019 Articles</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/2019_04_links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 11:50:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/2019_04_links/</guid>
      <description>Hi all! I thought I&#39;d update y&#39;all with some of my recent readings/watchings on the internet. (The picture above was taken in April 2019 during a hike to Cerro de la Cruz)
Thoughts on Life  How to Pick a Career (That Actually Fits You) | Wait But Why Wait but why has a nice illustration here of post-undergraduate meaning, in which our life paths are no-longer linear. I did not read the whole article but bits of it were inspiring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerro El Plomo</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/el_plomo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/el_plomo/</guid>
      <description>I did not summit Cerro El Plomo this past weekend.
Closing the trip on Sunday night, in Rodrigo&#39;s car we descended back down to Santiago from our trailhead, the ski resort of Valle Nevado, at 3000m. The drive back down was a spectacular solace &amp;ndash;up in the mountains, over two kilometers above Chile&#39;s primary metropolis, you could see glimpses of the sea of lights peeking between mountain canyons, contrasting the clean clear air and the celestial sky in the highlands with urban civilization, cosmopolitanism, and reality down below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 2019 Articles</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/2019_01_links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 11:50:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/2019_01_links/</guid>
      <description>Hi all! I thought I&#39;d update y&#39;all with some of my recent readings/watchings on the internet. Above is a picture from our hike in El Cani, Chile, Jan 2019.
Business Articles  Behind the Big Promises of the Micromobility Industry | CityLab What is the future of transportation? While there is industry hype on self-driving cars, I personally believe that micromobility (dockless bikes and scooters) are the nearer term solution. Fyre: The Greatest Party that Never Happened | Netflix This Netflix documentary, along with Hulu&#39;s take on the Fyre festival, is an introspective take on a failed music festival in 2017 and the lead-up to the disaster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cryptography Work</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 20:54:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/crypto/</guid>
      <description>Below is a series of summaries of my research in cryptography while I was a student at MIT.
Implementation of a Practical Leakage-Resilient ID Scheme (2016-2018) For my senior year at MIT, I participated in the MIT SuperUROP program as a MITRE Undergraduate Research and Innovation Scholar. My research topic was Implementing Leakage Resilient, Public Key Authentication Systems for Embedded Devices, working with Utsav Banerjee, Chiraag Juvekar and Prof. Anantha Chandrakasan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiking in 2018</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/hiking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/hiking/</guid>
      <description>I should probably be writing my thesis for my MEng, but I&#39;ll start off kindling the writing part of my mind by procrastinating for a bit.
In the past year after I completed my undergraduate degree, I&#39;ve been slowing spending more time finding more about who I am. During the MIT undergraduate semesters, which was one of the best times of my life, I had a lot on my plate, from rushing problem set deadline to photography event to party &amp;ndash;it was the work-hard, play-hard lifestyle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Urban Planning and Such</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/2018_urban/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 11:50:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/2018_urban/</guid>
      <description>A collection of thoughts and links on trains, planes, and more</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.875 Cryptography &amp; Cryptanalysis Lecture Videos</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.875/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.875/</guid>
      <description>During the Spring 2018 Semester, I took Vinod Vaikuntanathan and Shafi Goldwasser&#39;s Cryptography &amp;amp; Cryptanalysis (6.875) class. I filmed all but one lecture (oops I lost the video on MPC somwhere in the middle of class), providing a resource for current and future students to access the wonderful lectures. You can view the playlist here. The first recorded lecture is embedded below.
   Selected Press The lecture videos were featured on Hacker News.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ORGanized Interactions</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.824/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 20:54:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.824/</guid>
      <description>Context For our final project for the Distributed Systems Class at MIT (6.824), we have successfully implemented a command line interface text editor, such that multiple clients can collaborate on a single document and attain eventual consistency in the document through the use of operational transforms.
View our paper on our implementation here.
The link to the github repository with our source code is available here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack Punt Tool</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/hpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 06:47:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/hpt/</guid>
      <description>Context Along with MIT Student Cable, I helped film MIT&#39;s Musical Theater Guild (MTG)&amp;lsquo;s IAP 2017 production of Hack, Punt, Tool, which is an original musical about a fictional group of MIT students working on building a Hack at MIT.
Please enjoy the video below!   The lenses we used included a Nikon 70-200mm f2.8, Panasonic 7-14mm f4.0.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Digits via Audio-Visual Representations</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.867/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.867/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Our goal is to explore models for language learning (in this case learning numerical digits in their spoken and visual representations) in the manner that humans learn languages as children. Namely, children do not have intermediary text transcriptions in corresponding visual and audio inputs from the world around them; rather, they directly make connections between what they see and what they hear. In this paper, we construct models for the direct bi-directional classification of speech and images, inspired by a few research papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer 2016 Vlogs</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/2016_videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 06:47:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/2016_videos/</guid>
      <description>Context During the summer of 2016, I made a series of vlogs documenting my travels through Asia. My friend Jingyi Zhao and I took a one week trip to Thailand before heading to Tokyo for a week to participate in the MUSCAT program organized by the university of Tokyo. Here are four videos that I made documenting the trip.
1. Flight to Thailand   2. Bangkok   3. Chiang Mai   4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Tic Tac Toe AI</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.115/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.115/</guid>
      <description>For my final project, I built a 3D Tic Tac Toe game, complete with an AI for the user to play against. The input of the game used capacitave based sensing chips, and the output of the game was displayed on a VGA screen. I used my 8051 and R31JP to connect with my PSoC to process the user input and game engine.
Video   Github See my code and documentation here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.854 Advanced Algorithms Lecture Videos</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.854/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 06:46:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/6.854/</guid>
      <description>During the Spring 2016 Semester, I took Ankur Moitra&#39;s Advanced Algorithms (6.854) class. With the help of my friends Sitara Persad and Shraman Ray Chaudhuri, we filmed all but two lectures, providing a resource for current and future students to access Prof. Moitra&#39;s wonderful lectures. You can view the playlist here. The first recorded lecture is embedded below.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT Sophomore Mixer Series</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/2015_mixer_series/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 11:50:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/2015_mixer_series/</guid>
      <description>Over IAP 2015 (MIT Speak for our January break), Justine Jang and I worked with Fred Daso and the MIT 2017 Class Council on the Mixer Series project as a way to connect MIT sophomores with each other.
 What we did MIT is a very diverse community, but students are very busy. So how does one meet new people outside of her daily life cycle of classes, clubs, psetting, and her friend group?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>