<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>articles on Andrew Xia</title>
    <link>https://qandrew.github.io/tags/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in articles on Andrew Xia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 11:50:20 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://qandrew.github.io/tags/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>April 2019 Articles</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/2019_04_links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 11:50:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/2019_04_links/</guid>
      <description>Hi all! I thought I&#39;d update y&#39;all with some of my recent readings/watchings on the internet. (The picture above was taken in April 2019 during a hike to Cerro de la Cruz)
Thoughts on Life  How to Pick a Career (That Actually Fits You) | Wait But Why Wait but why has a nice illustration here of post-undergraduate meaning, in which our life paths are no-longer linear. I did not read the whole article but bits of it were inspiring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 2019 Articles</title>
      <link>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/2019_01_links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 11:50:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://qandrew.github.io/blog/2019_01_links/</guid>
      <description>Hi all! I thought I&#39;d update y&#39;all with some of my recent readings/watchings on the internet. Above is a picture from our hike in El Cani, Chile, Jan 2019.
Business Articles  Behind the Big Promises of the Micromobility Industry | CityLab What is the future of transportation? While there is industry hype on self-driving cars, I personally believe that micromobility (dockless bikes and scooters) are the nearer term solution. Fyre: The Greatest Party that Never Happened | Netflix This Netflix documentary, along with Hulu&#39;s take on the Fyre festival, is an introspective take on a failed music festival in 2017 and the lead-up to the disaster.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>